<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Florida Department of Revenue</origin><pubdate>2017</pubdate><title>Alachua County, FL 100 scale, 0.5' pixel digital 4-band color orthoimagery (2017)</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>raster digital data</geoform><serinfo><sername>Orthoimages – 2017</sername><issue>Alachua County, FL</issue></serinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Tallahassee, FL</pubplace><publish>Florida Department of Revenue</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This metadata describes the digital ortho imagery covering a selected area of Alachua County, FL. This 1"=100' scale imagery is comprised of 4-band (RGBIR) color orthoimagery with a GSD (Ground Sample Distance) of 0.5'. Imagery was collected with Vexcel Ultracam Eagle (UCEagle) large format aerial sensor and processed with Inpho (Trimble) Photogrammetry software. Imagery is projected in State Plane Coordinate System, Florida north using the Lambert Conformal Conic map projection parameters.</abstract><purpose>A digital orthoimage is a geometrically accurate image record of landscape conditions at the time of the corresponding aerial imagery. As such, the digital orthoimage is useful for a variety of applications, such as environmental monitoring, facility engineering/maintenance, city/county planning, property line review, etc. The digital orthoimage can be used alone or as a raster basemap for corresponding vector line mapping.</purpose><supplinf>The aircraft used for image acquisition was a twin engine Piper Navajo, tail number N3547J. The imaging system used was a Vexcel Ultracam Eagle (UCEagle), SN 80214441, large format aerial sensor. The UCEagle radiometric resolution in each color band is 12 bits. Average flight altitude was 9550' above mean sea level (AMSL) or 9450' above ground level (AGL). Date of camera calibration was 20140410. Calibration Method: The geometric calibration is based on a set of 84 images of a defined geometry target with 394 GCPs. Number of point measurements for the panchromatic camera: 18730. Number of point measurements for the multispectral camera: 72871. Determination of the image parameters by Least Squares Adjustment. Software used for the adjustment: BINGO (GIP Eng. Aalen, Germany). The four UCEagle bands record data in the following manner: Band 1 (blue); Band 2 (green); Band 3 (red); Band 4 (NIR). Project Projection, Datums and Units: Projection – State Plane Coordinate System (SPCS) Florida north zone. Horizontal datum – North American Datum of 1983(2011). Vertical datum – National Geodetic Vertical Datum of 1988(GEOID12A). Units – U.S. Survey foot.  The bounding coordinates in this metadata file represent the bounding coordinates for all image tiles in the selected project area of Alachua County as a whole, not an individual tile.</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><mdattim><sngdate><caldate>20170108</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170130</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170209</caldate></sngdate></mdattim></timeinfo><current>Ground condition</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Annually</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-82.67366859</westbc><eastbc>-82.03244120</eastbc><northbc>29.94953180</northbc><southbc>29.40307204</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>Aerial Imagery</themekt><themekey>UltraCam X</themekey><themekey>UCx</themekey><themekey>Digital aerial image</themekey><themekey>Orthoimage</themekey></theme><place><placekt>FL</placekt><placekey>Alachua County</placekey><placekey>Florida</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>The orthoimages were collected and produced under the supervision of a licensed Professional Surveyor and Mapper.  Use of these data requires a general understanding of GIS and spatial data.</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Charles Russell</cntper><cntorg>Florida Department of Revenue (FL-DOR)</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Property Tax Oversight</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing</addrtype><address>2450 Shumard Oak Blvd.  Room 2-3200</address><city>Tallahassee</city><state>FL</state><postal>32399-0126</postal><country>U.S.</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>850-617-8867</cntvoice><cntfax>850-617-6113</cntfax><cntemail>Charles.Russell@floridarevenue.com</cntemail><hours>Unknown</hours></cntinfo></ptcontac><datacred>Florida Department of Revenue and Kucera International Inc.</datacred><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; TKME 2.9.20</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>See Horizontal and Vertical Accuracy reports.  There are no Attributes in this data set.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Compliance with the accuracy standard was ensured by the placement of GPS ground control prior to the acquisition of aerial imagery.  The following checks were performed:
1. The ground control and airborne GPS/INS data stream were validated through an aerotriangulation bundle adjustment using Inpho Match-AT software.  The residuals of the adjustment met the required standards with the results fully outlined in an AT report.
2. Digital orthoimagery was validated through a visual inspection of control points, edge matching and general image quality.</logic><complete>Orthoimages are visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no gaps or image misplacements exist within and between adjacent images.  These images are derived by mosaicing multiple images to ensure complete coverage of the project area.
The following methods were used to ensure image quality:
1. Use of targeted ground control during image acquisition.
2. Use of GPS/INS during image acquisition.
3. Checking of controls against ortho product.
4. Post ortho accuracy approval checks for overall image quality (tone, color balance, etc.).</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>FL DOR specifies orthoimage mapping will meet or exceed a verified horizontal accuracy of 2.53 feet at the 95% confidence interval (1.46 feet RMSE) as tested in accordance with the FGDC Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards, Part 3: National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy (NSSDA). A minimum of 25 independent image checkpoints within the Alachua County project area will be used for verification.  Check points will be distributed so that points are spaced at intervals of at least ten (10) percent of the diagonal distance across the dataset and at least twenty (20) percent of the points are located in each quadrant of the dataset. The Consultant is not expected to correct for "building lean" in urban areas.  For more information please see project related minimum technical standards report.</horizpar><qhorizpa><horizpav>0.55</horizpav><horizpae>This data set was tested in accordance with Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards Part 3:  National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy (NSSDA), FGDC-STD-007.3-1998 which is then related to NMAS as defined in Appendix 3-D Section 2.  The RMSE of of twenty-six (26) checkpoints in the orthoimagery was tested with a resultant RMSE of 0.32'.  NSSDA horizontal accuracy is 1.7308*RMSE_r or 1.7308*0.32 = 0.55'.  NSSDA Horizontal accuracy meets or exceeds the project requirement of 2.53' at 95% confidence.</horizpae></qhorizpa></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>No vertical accuracy analysis required for the orthoimages.</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Kucera International Inc.</origin><pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate><title>Aerial imagery</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>raster digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>None</pubplace><publish>None</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1200</srcscale><typesrc>disc</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><mdattim><sngdate><caldate>20170108</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170130</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170209</caldate></sngdate></mdattim></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>IMG</srccitea><srccontr>The aerial imagery was captured with a Microsoft UltraCam Eagle (UCEagle) large format digital aerial camera. The UCEagle uses an image frame based method of data collection with multiple, precisely registered CCDs collecting nadir oriented images along planned flight lines. Each CCD array collects data in one of the pan, red, green, blue or NIR spectral bands. This results in one image per frame CCD. Simultaneously with image capture, position and orientation information is collected with a Novatel SPAN GPS/INS system. The aerial images and GPS/INS data are post processed on the ground to produce color, color infrared or black and white digital images used for softcopy aerotriangulation, DEM generation, mapping and orthoimage production.  Aerotriangulation refines the exterior orientation parameters (X, Y, Z, Omega, Phi, Kappa) of the recorded GPS/INS orientations.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Van Horne</origin><pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate><title>Ground control</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>Tabular digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>None</pubplace><publish>None</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>disc</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>201701</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>CONT</srccitea><srccontr>Fifteen (15) targeted or image identifiable  ground control were used to create a digital control file and control report as well as QC check of ortho accuracy. Predefined points within the county are either targeted or photo identifiable ground features visible in the imagery.  These ground control points along with their precise coordinates are used in the AT process and to check the horizontal accuracy of the resulting orthoimages.  An additional twenty-six (26) GCPs are surveyed to act as post-rectification independent check points for NSSDA accuracy computations and reporting.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Kucera International Inc.</origin><pubdate>2017</pubdate><title>Digital elevation model</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>Raster digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Unknown</pubplace><publish>Unknown</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>disc</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><mdattim><sngdate><caldate>20170109</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170112</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170202</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20170210</caldate></sngdate></mdattim></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>DEM</srccitea><srccontr>The DEM is a new lidar DEM acquired in conjunction with the aerial imagery for use in the orthorectification process. The lidar data is post processed to a bare earth dataset, projected to the project coordinate system and resampled to a 10 foot grid in GeoTIFF format.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Kucera International Inc.</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>Tile definition</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>Vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Unknown</pubplace><publish>Unknown</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>disc</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>2017</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>TLDEF</srccitea><srccontr>The tile definition is used to cut orthorectified imagery into manageable, usable images. Each tile is 5000' X 5000'.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Kucera International Inc.</origin><pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate><title>Orthorectified imagery</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>raster digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>None</pubplace><publish>None</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1200</srcscale><typesrc>disc</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>2017</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>OIMG1</srccitea><srccontr>This first level of orthorectified images are the product of using the AT solution and the DEM in Inpho Orthomaster software. This first level of orthorectified imagery is the product of using the aerotriangulation solution and the DEM in Inpho Orthomaster software software. These orthorectified images overlap with adjacent imagery but have yet to be mosaiced into seamless tiled orthos.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Kucera International Inc.</origin><pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate><title>Tiled Orthoimage</title><edition>1.0</edition><geoform>raster digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>None</pubplace><publish>None</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>1200</srcscale><typesrc>disc, DVD or online</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>2017</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>Ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>OIMG2</srccitea><srccontr>The tiled orthoimage is the result of mosaicing orthorectified imagery with Inpho Systems Orthovista software and using the tile definition to cut into seamless orthoimages. Orthovista merges all the input orthoimages and creates seamless color balanced image tiles based on the tile definition bounds. The orthoimage tiles are 5000'wide by 5000' high and projected in Florida State Plane Coordinate System, north zone.</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>At selected locations throughout the site, accurate GPS coordinates and elevations are surveyed and the points are marked with targets which will be visible in the aerial imagery.</procdesc><srcused>Cont</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>CONT</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>New digital, color aerial imagery of the site is acquired using the UCx camera.  Airborne GPS/IMU data is recorded along with the imagery</procdesc><srcused>None</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>IMG</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Imagery and GPS/IMU data is downloaded from disc on the plane to disc on the ground.  GPS/IMU mission data is processed together with simultaneously collected ground-based GPS base station data in forward and reverse directions.  This precisely determines the aerial camera's position and orientation in the terrain (project) coordinate system and allows for correct orientation of the imagery.</procdesc><srcused>IMG</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>IMG</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Using the processed GPS/IMU data and correctly oriented imagery, a bundle adjustment is computed (AT) in Inpho Match-AT software.</procdesc><srcused>IMG, CONT</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>AT</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Orthorectified imagery is produced using Inpho Systems (Trimble) Orthomaster software.</procdesc><srcused>IMG, DEM, AT</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>OIMG1</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Orthorectified imagery is mosaiced, locally color-balanced and cut to the tile definition boundaries using Inpho OrthoVista software.  The tiled orthos are checked for accuracy against the surveyed ground control before further image editing.</procdesc><srcused>OIMG1, CONT</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>OIMG2</srcprod></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Tiled orthoimages then go through a rigorous manual QC process to evaluate for remaining hotspots (sun reflectance over water), tone quality, color balance and the feathering area between flightlines.  Any imperfections at this point are manually edited.  If necessary, the tiled images are then converted to required format.  All images are either recorded on DVD, transferred to HD or posted on FTP for client access.</procdesc><srcused>OIMG2</srcused><procdate>2017</procdate><srcprod>OIMG2</srcprod></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Raster</direct><rastinfo><rasttype>Pixel</rasttype><rowcount>5000</rowcount><colcount>5000</colcount></rastinfo></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn><spcs><spcszone>0903</spcszone><lambertc><stdparll>29.5833333333</stdparll><stdparll>30.75000000</stdparll><longcm>-84.50000000</longcm><latprjo>29.00000000</latprjo><feast>1968500.000</feast><fnorth>0.000000000</fnorth></lambertc></spcs></gridsys><planci><plance>Coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.5</absres><ordres>0.5</ordres></coordrep><plandu>U.S. Survey Foot</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983 (2011)</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988(Geoid12B)</altdatum><altres>0.1</altres><altunits>U.S. Survey Foot</altunits><altenc>Implicit coordinate</altenc></altsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><overview><eaover>Color orthoimages are comprised of pixels. Each pixel is assigned a value of 0 to 255. That number will refer to a color look-up table which contains red, green and blue (RGB) values (green, red NIR for false color IR images), each from 0 to 255, for that pixel within the image.</eaover><eadetcit>The four UCEagle color bands record data in the following manner: Band 1 (blue); Band 2 (green); Band 3 (red); Band 4 (Near InfraRed (NIR)). For color infrared (CIR) imagery the pixel values of the green, red and NIR bands are assigned to look-up table values for the visually perceived blue, green and red spectrum resulting in a false color infrared image, i.e. objects that are highly reflective in the NIR band will appear red in a CIR image.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Beverly Renard</cntper><cntorg>Florida Resources &amp; Environmental Analysis Center (FREAC)</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Technology Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>296 Champions Way</address><address>Room C2200 UCC</address><city>Tallahassee</city><state>FL</state><postal>32306-2641</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>850-644-2305</cntvoice><cntemail>brenard@fsu.edu</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Approximately 1/3 of the state is flown each year.  Complete state coverage is available.  Most imagery is 1-foot resolution; occasionally a county is 1/2-foot resolution.</resdesc><distliab>None</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>MrSID</formname><formvern>6</formvern><formspec>MrSID</formspec><formcont>MrSID</formcont><filedec>MrSID</filedec><transize>255</transize></digtinfo><digtopt><offoptn><offmedia>External Hard Drive</offmedia><recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt></offoptn></digtopt></digform><fees>$100 plus tax and shipping</fees><ordering>Available by sending external USB hard drive (at least 300 GB) to FREAC.  Cost is $100, plus tax and shipping, which is invoiced when the drive is returned.  Please include a note indicating that you would like to load the most current high resolution (1 foot or better) imagery that is in State Plane NAD83 coordinate system.</ordering><turnarnd>Approximately 1 week</turnarnd></stdorder><custom>Size of statewide data set is approximately 255GB.  Available by sending external hard drive to FREAC.  Cost is $100, plus tax and shipping.</custom></distinfo><metainfo><metd>2017</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Florida Department of Revenue Property Tax Oversight</cntorg><cntper>Mapping and GIS Section</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing</addrtype><address>2450 Shumard Oak Blvd.  Room 2-3200</address><city>Tallahassee</city><state>FL</state><postal>32399-0126</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>850-617-8867</cntvoice><cntfax>850-617-6113</cntfax><hours>8:00 am. to 5:00 pm.</hours></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo></metadata>